intpforum.com 2019-04-12

# INTP Forum Privacy Policy | INTP Forum

## INTPForum Privacy Policy

The policy: This privacy policy is for this website; [www.intpforum.com] and served by [URLJET, 1712 Pioneer Ave, Cheyenne, WY 82001, United States ] and governs the privacy of its users who choose to use it. It explains how we comply with the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation), the DPA (Data Protection Act) [pre GDPR enforcement] and the PECR (Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations). 

This policy will explain areas of this website that may affect your privacy and personal details, how we process, collect, manage and store those details and how your rights under the GDPR, DPA & PECR are adhere to. Additionally it will explain the use of cookies or software, advertising or commercial sponsorship from third parties and the download of any documents, files or software made available to you (if any) on this website. Further explanations may be provided for specific pages or features of this website in order to help you understand how we, this website and its third parties (if any) interact with you and your computer / device in order to serve it to you. Our contact information is provided if you have any questions. 

### The DPA & GDPR May 2018

We and this website complies to the DPA (Data Protection Act 1998) and already complies to the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) which comes into affect from May 2018. We will update this policy accordingly after the completion of the UK's exit from the European Union. 

### Use of Cookies

This website uses cookies to better the users experience while visiting the website. As required by legislation, where applicable this website uses a cookie control system, allowing the user to give explicit permission or to deny the use of /saving of cookies on their computer / device. 

What are cookies? Cookies are small files saved to the user's computers hard drive that track, save and store information about the user's interactions and usage of the website. This allows the website, through its server to provide the users with a tailored experience within this website. Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and its external serving vendors or use the cookie control system if available upon their first visit. 

### Information given to the Forum

Intpforum does not share information with others, and this information is at present what you willingly offer at registration; including the name given, the user-name chosen, any email addresses, and such optional information you decide to include in your profile and posts. 

Do not ever include real names, addresses or any personally identifiable information. Should you do so this is utterly at your own risk and responsibility. Anything you post on the forum becomes the property of the forum to use, although you maintain full copyright and any other rights in the form of post (and as such you can repost it or use it any way you wish). 

Email is required to open an account and protect your exclusive use of your own account: age is necessary to ensure minors do not view inappropriate content. Other information you offer is at your discretion. 

### Website Visitor Tracking

This website uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. The software will save a cookie to your computers hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website, but will not store, save or collect personal information. We do not use Google Analytics --- nota bene: Websites using GA enable Google to track one from site to site. Nor are the cPanel integral statistics, such as AWStats, viewed by us. 

### Adverts and Sponsored Links

This website contains no advertising. 

Nor is any personalized tracking or offering allowed. Any links whatsoever are clicked on at the user's own risk. 

### Downloads & Media Files

Any downloadable documents, files or media made available on this website are provided to users at their own risk. While all precautions have been undertaken to ensure only genuine downloads are available users are advised to verify their authenticity using third party anti virus software or similar applications. 

We accept no responsibility for third party downloads and downloads provided by external third party websites and advise users to verify their authenticity using third party anti virus software or similar applications. 

### Contact & Communication With Us

Users contacting this us through this website do so at their own discretion and provide any such personal details requested at their own risk. Your personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use. 

Where we have clearly stated and made you aware of the fact, and where you have given your express permission, we may use your details to send you products/services information through a mailing list system. This is done in accordance with the regulations named in 'The policy' above. So far this has never happened. 

The DPO (Data Protection Officer) is the main admin, at present Ragnar. 

### Email Mailing List

We operate an email mailing list program, integral to XenForo's Forum software, for the registration of users. 

### Deletion

We do not delete or prune members' posts and information; but will consider requests from a legal source to erase posts with personal details if such have been posted in disregard of our requested policy. Members cannot request their account deleted (except for parts with such personal information). 

### Shortened URL's

URL shortening is a technique used on the web to shorten URL's (Uniform Resource Locators) to something substantially shorter. This technique is especially used in social media and looks similar to this (example: http://bit.ly/zyVUBo). Users should take caution before clicking on shortened URL links and verify their authenticity before proceeding. 

We cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite our best efforts. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and we cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned. 

### Social Media Policy & Usage

We might adopt a Social Media Policy to ensure our business and our staff will conduct themselves accordingly online. While we may have official profiles on social media platforms users are advised to verify authenticity of such profiles before engaging with, or sharing information with such profiles. We will never ask for user passwords or personal details on social media platforms. Users are advised to conduct themselves appropriately when engaging with us on social media. 

There may be instances where our website features social sharing buttons, which help share web content directly from web pages to the respective social media platforms. You use social sharing buttons at your own discretion and accept that doing so may publish content to your social media profile feed or page. You can find further information about some social media privacy and usage policies in the resources section below. 

v.3.0 November 2017 Edited & customised by:INTPForum 

### Resources & Further Information

Based on the GDPR Website Privacy Policy Notice by Jamie King from Wales in the last link, with gratitude. 

v.3.0 May 2018 Edited & customised by: INTPForum
